Keith McMahon

 $2016\,SW$ 98th Street // Seattle, WA 98106

Phone: 206.227.9096 // E-Mail: k-mac13@comcast.net

Objective

With 20+ years of experience in all phases of technical delivery – from concept through deployment – I bring a wide range of insight to my project teams. I have created solutions for multi-media CD-ROMs, written copy and developed web applications for humanitarian organizations, delivered the web framework and content for the worldwide release of a major operating system, produced campaign experiences for various Xbox entertainment titles, along with both internal and client marketing and brand materials. I value the community aspect of teams working closely together – a process that grows individual skills, strengthens the team, and produces deliverables that exceed expectations and get our clients promotions.

My hope is that my background and experience will pique your interest.

Experience

POP // Technical Analyst 4/2012 - Present

- Work with clients and internal leads to pursue, scope, brainstorm, and define project deliverables
- Lead the estimation and assumptions gathering process for technology project deliverables
- · Partner with creative discipline leads to review and comment on wireframe, design, and content drafts
- Create project documentation and training manuals, technical and functional specifications, approach review and connectivity documents, and project work items
- Manage technical delivery workflow, participate in daily stand-ups, lead build reviews, and present to and lead client discussions

Ascentium Corporation (rebranded as SMITH) // Associate Partner, Technical Director

4/2004 - 4/2012

- Internal roles and responsibilities
 - Technology Director and Technology Lead for Ascentium Studio
 - Technology Director and Technology Lead for Ascentium's Microsoft account team
 - Member of Ascentium's Microsoft account leadership team
 - Member of Ascentium's agency leadership team
 - Discipline Lead for front-end developers (multi-locale, cross discipline, for as many as 20 technologists)
 - RFP review, pitch development and review, pitch delivery
 - Project estimation, process review, and staffing
- Client project roles and responsibilities
 - Technology leadership, site architecture
 - Wireframe and design comp review
 - Web site architecture, development, and production
 - Web graphic production
 - Primary Ascentium client accounts: Microsoft, McKesson

Hindsight Now // Freelance Web Developer/Designer	2001-2004
Go-to-Market Strategies // Creative Services Specialist	2002
Chase Bobko // Senior Production Lead, Creative Services Specialist	1999-2001
ST Labs (later Data Dimensions) // Software Test Lead, Webmaster, Creative Services Specialist	1995-1998
Ministry Involvement	
Bethany Presbyterian Church // Men's Ministry	ongoing
Bethany Presbyterian Church // Session	2002-2005
Bethany Presbyterian Church // High School Youth Leader	1993-2001
Young Life // High School Youth Leader / Work Crew / Summer Staff	1987-1992
Education	
Ascentium // Delivery Management Academy	2011
Extraordinary Learning // 21st Century Leadership	2010
California State University, Chico // B.A. English	1992

Skills

For skills, endorsements, recommendations, and other experience, please see my LinkedIn profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/cecilhayduke